Alok Raj

Pune, India (+91)8240159173 alokr417@gmail.com

Full Stack JavaScript Developer

linkedin@alok722 github@alok722 alokraj.me

Current **Web UI Developer** at Globant with **2+** years of experience specializing in **JavaScript technologies**. A Super nerd who loves **JavaScript** & its frameworks, libraries and enjoys customizing all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer (Web UI Developer)

March 2021 — Present

Globant India Pvt. Ltd.

Pune, IN

- Been part of project right from discovery phase and led the development of initial phase of **Micro Front-end** Apps with **React.Js** using **Module Federation Approach** in Design/Build phase.
- Built various modules of client's banking web apps with **Unit Test** code coverage of **80%+**.
- Built several customizable **custom hooks** & **reusable components** to reduce code redundancy during initial phase of development which overall **increased** the productivity of new joiners in project by around **10**%.
- Tech stacks: React. Js with Typescript & Redux, RxJS, CSS Modules, SCSS, React Testing Library, Jest, i18n

Software Engineer (MEAN Stack Developer)

June 2019 — Mar 2021

Tata Consultancy Services

Bangalore, IN

- Implemented a scheduler jobs microservice & companion webapp to automate data sync & notification service.
- Developed an easy-to-use SMTP RESTful API server replicating AWS SES template system.
- Implemented **Dynamic** form template system which helped reducing development time approximately by 15%.
- Developed a Mongo migration utility web-app to help with data administration tasks using vanilla JavaScript.
- Implemented a TCS internal web-app to manage client's projects, allocation and Billing related accounts.
- Tech stacks: Angular 7+, Angular Material, RxJS, Node.Js, Express.Js, MongoDB, Microservice arch., Mocha, Chai

• Tech stacks. Angular 17, Angular Material, RXD3, Node.D3, Express.D3, Mongobb, Microservice arch., Mocha, Char

GroupClap EdTech Pvt. Ltd.

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

Customer facing WordPress, static websites & Android apps.

• Tech stacks: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, WordPress, Android, PHP.

INTERN Feb. 2018 - June 2018

Vedas Technocrats Pvt. Ltd.

Kolkata, IN

Kolkata, IN

- Developed front-end of many Android apps Integrated APIs & SDKs to make apps more functional.
- Tech stack: Android.

SKILLS

INTERN

Front-end: React, Vue.js, Angular 2+, Redux, Next.js, RxJs, Vuex, Nuxt.js, HTML, CSS, SASS, MaterialUI, Angular Material

Back-end: NodeJs, ExpressJs, NestJs, Fastify

Language: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java

Database: MongoDB (Mongoose), Neo4j, Redis, PostgreSQL, MS-SQL

Others: Docker, AWS, Socket.IO, PWA, Git & GitHub, AGILE, JSDoc & TSDoc, Unit Testing, Open source enthusiast

Soft-skills: Excellent communication skill, Team Work Spirit, Leadership skill

EDUCATION

B. Tech. in Computer Science and Engineering, MCKV Institute of Engineering,

Aug. 2015 - June 2019

A graduate with an aggregate of 8.08 DGPA having good understanding of Software Development Life Cycle.

PROJECT

All my small & medium level projects are available at my github(60+ repositories). Click here

ACTIVITIES & ACHIEVEMENTS

Co-Founder Creator of Open Source Software Development Team (opendevs) with 5+ open source projects.

Recognition Received 3 fantabulous awards within 5 months at Globant.

Instructor Acted as a Instructor & trained peer associates on MongoDB during my tenure at TCS.

Tech Bairn Gave training to 30+ students on MERN stack along with my friend as opendevs initiative.

Recognition Received 10+ awards during my tenure at TCS.